TransitOps. Fleet operations, finally under control.
Every day, transport companies lose hours to spreadsheets and phone calls.
The same vehicle gets booked twice. A suspended driver ends up on a live route.
Maintenance slips through the cracks. Fuel costs pile up with no clear picture of ROI.
Managers guess at utilization. Finance chases receipts. Safety teams react instead of prevent.
TransitOps is a transport operations ERP built to replace that fragmentation.
One platform for fleet, drivers, dispatches, maintenance, fuel, and financial oversight.
Sign in with secure JWT authentication. Each user sees only what their role allows.
Admin. Fleet Manager. Safety Officer. Financial Analyst. Driver.
Route guards on the frontend. Role checks on every API endpoint on the backend.
Welcome to TransitOps Core — your fleet operations and ROI intelligence control center.
Four KPI cards update in real time from server-side aggregations.
Fleet Utilization — what percentage of your active fleet is en route right now.
Operational Cost — fuel, maintenance, and approved expenses combined.
Estimated Revenue — calculated at two dollars fifty per mile of completed trips.
Return on Investment — the efficiency of every asset in your fleet.
Below that, live charts: monthly fuel expense trends, maintenance cost by type,
and a fleet status pie chart showing Active, On Trip, and In Maintenance allocation.
The sidebar shows your three most recent dispatches and compliance alerts from the notification system.
In the Vehicles module, register a new asset with plate number, make, model, and payload capacity.
Search by plate. Filter by status. Duplicate registrations are blocked at the database level.
Inspect any vehicle to view per-asset metrics — fuel cost, maintenance spend, distance driven, and ROI.
In the Operator Registry, link a driver to a system user account and record license details.
License expiry is validated at dispatch time. Safety scores display on every profile.
Now the core workflow — dispatch a trip from the Trips module.
Select an Active vehicle. Assign an Active operator. Enter origin, destination, and cargo weight.
The UI warns you if cargo exceeds payload. The server enforces it before anything is saved.
On successful dispatch, vehicle and driver status automatically transition to On Trip.
Complete the trip with an end odometer reading. Both return to Active. Vehicle mileage syncs instantly.
Schedule maintenance and the vehicle is removed from dispatch — status moves to In Maintenance.
Resolve the work order with cost and mechanic details. The vehicle is available again.
Log fuel entries with quantity, cost, and odometer. Record expense claims by category.
Approve pending expenses. Dashboard KPIs refresh automatically — no manual spreadsheet updates.
Analytics on the dashboard show fuel trends, maintenance breakdown, and fleet allocation over six months.
Per-vehicle metrics deliver fuel efficiency and ROI for individual assets.
Now — what happens when someone tries to break the rules?
Dispatch a vehicle already on trip — rejected. Assign a suspended driver — blocked.
Use a driver with an expired license — stopped. Exceed cargo capacity — denied.
Try to dispatch a vehicle in maintenance — the system says no. Every failure returns a clear message.
These rules live in the service layer — not in the UI — so they cannot be bypassed.
The architecture: React nineteen with Vite and TypeScript on the frontend.
Express and MongoDB on the backend. JWT with refresh tokens. Role-based access control.
Clean separation — routes, controllers, services, repositories, and Mongoose models.
Input validation with express-validator and Zod. TanStack Query for server state. Recharts for analytics.
Docker Compose for one-command deployment. Integration tests cover the full dispatch lifecycle.
TransitOps replaces spreadsheet chaos with enforced workflows and live financial intelligence.
One platform. One source of truth. Built for teams that move the world.
Thank you, Odoo Hackathon judges. We are TransitOps.